Guide to the Stanford University, Student Center for Innovation in Research and Education, Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Stanford University, Student Center for Innovation in Research and Education, records
1969-1985
SC0326
Stanford University. Student Center for Innovation in Research and Education.
16 Linear feet
Correspondence, memoranda, minutes, reports, proposals, financial records, publications, and other records pertaining to the administration of SCIRE, sponsored projects and internships, and the SCIRE Innovation Fund.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, 1986.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
SCIRE (Student Center for Innovation in Research and Education) was established in 1970 to initiate and focus attention on educational change and increase students' responsibility for their own education. It offered academic credit for individual and group projects and internships and provided funding for innovative projects. Initially under the auspices of the Dean of Undergraduate Studies, it was transferred to the domain of the School of Humanities and Sciences in 1982. It ceased operations in 1985.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence, memoranda, minutes, reports, proposals, financial records, publications, and other records pertaining to the administration of SCIRE, sponsored projects and internships, and the SCIRE Innovation Fund.
Access Terms
Stanford University. Student Center for Innovation in Research and Education.; Educational change.; Educational innovations.
Collection Contents
- Records, Accession ARCH-2005-290
  - SCTR 33 Assisting the Task Force on Homosexuality, Maid Haimson, Spring 1971 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - SCTR 199 History, Myth and Culture of the Homosexual, Donna Lee, et. al., Winter 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Final papers for Gay history March 1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - SCTR 199B The Homosexual: Liberator or Martyr, Joel Roberts, Spring 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Records, Accession ARCH-2006-289
  - A Guide to Off-Campus Living, 1975 [SCIRE pub] (Box 1)
  - Dick and Jane at Stanford, a SCIRE Catalog (Box 1)
  - Internships at Stanford: A Guide to Internship Opportunities Available through Campus Organizations, September 1978 [SCIRE pub] (Box 1)
  - folder: EDP General / Half Time for Student Co-Direct., 1976 (Box 1)
  - folder: Job Reclassification – Co-director, 1973-76 (Box 1)